This is a world-changing invention.
هذا إختراع سيغيّر العالم.
The smoke alarm has saved perhaps hundreds of thousands
جرس الدخان ربما حفظ مئات الآلاف
of lives, worldwide.
من الأرواح ، عالمياً.
But smoke alarms don't prevent fires.
لكن جرس الدخان لا يحمي من الحرائق.
Every year in the USA, over 20,000 are killed or injured
كل عام في الولايات المتحدة، أكثر من 20,000 يموتوا أو يجرحوا
with 350,000 home fires.
بسبب 350,000 حريق منزلي.
And one of the main causes of all these fires is electricity.
وأحد المسببات الرئيسية لكل هذه الحرائق هي الكهرباء.
What if we could prevent electrical fires
ماذا لو أمكننا منع الحرائق الكهربائية
before they start?
قبل أن تبدأ؟
Well, a couple of friends and I figured out how to do this.
حسناً، أكتشفت أنا ومجموعة من الأصدقاء كيفية عمل هذا.
So how does electricity ignite residential fires?
اذا كيف تسبب الكهرباء الحرائق المنزلية؟
Well it turns out that the main causes
حسناً تبيّن أن الأسباب الرئيسية
are faulty and misused appliances and electrical wiring.
تنتج عن خطأ أو سوء إستخدام الأجهزة المنزلية وتوصيل الأسلاك.
Our invention had to address all of these issues.
توجب على إختراعنا حل كل هذه المشاكل.
So what about circuit breakers?
اذا ماذا عن قواطع الدوائر الكهربية؟
Well, Thomas Edison invented the circuit breaker in 1879.
حسناً، أخترع توماس أديسون قاطع الدائرة عام 1879.
This is 130-year-old technology,
هذه تقنية عمرها 130 عاماً.
and this is a problem, because over 80 percent
وهذه مشكلة. لأن ما يزيد على 80 في المائة
of all home electrical fires
لحرائق المنازل بفعل الكهرباء
start below the safety threshold of circuit breakers.
بدأت دون نقطة السلامة لقواطع الدائرة.
Hmmm ...
همممم...
So we considered all of this. And we realized
وضعنا في الإعتبار كل هذا. وعرفنا
that electrical appliances
أن الأجهزة الكهربائية المنزلية
must be able to communicate directly
يجب أن تقدر على الإتصال مباشرة
with the power receptacle itself.
مع مقبس الكهرباء نفسه.
Any electrical device -- an appliance, an extension cord, whatever --
أي جهاز كهربائي، منزلي، سلك توصيل، أي كان،
must be able to tell the power outlet,
يجب أن يقدر على التواصل مع مقبس الكهرباء،
"Hey, power outlet,
" يا، مقبس الكهرباء،
I'm drawing too much current. Shut me off now, before I start a fire."
أنا أستهلك الكثير من التيار. أطفئني الآن، قبل أن أبدأ حريقاً".
And the power outlet needs to be smart enough to do it.
ويجب أن يكون مقبس الكهرباء ذكياً بما يكفي لفعل ذلك.
So here is what we did. We put a 10-cent digital transponder,
اذا هذا ما فعلناه. وضعنا 10 في المائة مستيجباً رقمياً،
a data tag, in the appliance plug.
وآمر بيانات، في مقبس الجهاز المنزلي.
And we put an inexpensive, wireless data reader inside the receptacle
ووضعنا قارئ بيانات رخيص داخل المستجيب
so they could communicate.
بحيث يستطيعان التواصل.
Now, every home electrical system
الآن، كل نظام كهرباء منزلي
becomes an intelligent network.
يصبح شبكة ذكية
The appliance's safe operating parameters
معلمات التشغيل الآمنة للأجهزة المنزلية
are embedded into its plug.
مضمّنة داخل المقبس.
If too much current is flowing,
اذا مرّ تيار كهربائي كثيف،
the intelligent receptacle turns itself off,
يطفئ المستجيب الذكي نفسه،
and prevents another fire from starting.
ويمنع حدوث حريق آخر.
We call this technology EFCI,
نسمي هذه التكنلوجيا EFCI،
Electrical Fault Circuit Interrupter.
قاطع الدائرة الكهربية الخاطئة.
Okay, two more points. Every year in the USA,
حسناً، نقطتان أخريات. كل سنة في الولايات المتحدة،
roughly 2,500 children
حوالي 2,500 طفل
are admitted to emergency rooms for shock and burn injuries
يدخلوا الى غرفة العناية المركزة بسبب الصدمة وجروح حرائق
related to electrical receptacles. And this is crazy.
مرتبطة بالمستجيب الكهربي. وهذا جنوني.
An intelligent receptacle prevents injuries
المستجيب الذكي يمنع الجروح
because the power is always off,
لأن الكهرباء دائماً مطفأة،
until an intelligent plug is detected. Simple.
حتى يتم يضبط المقبس الذكي. ببساطة.
Now, besides saving lives,
الآن، بجانب حماية الأرواح،
perhaps the greatest benefit of intelligent power
ربما الفائدة الأعظم من الكهرباء الذكية
is in its energy savings.
في حفاظها على الطاقة.
This invention will reduce global energy consumption
سيقلل هذا الإختراع من إستهلاك الطاقة عالمياً
by allowing remote control and automation
بالسماح بالتحكم عن بعد والتشغيل الآلي
of every outlet in every home and business.
لكل مقبس في كل بيت ومكان عمل.
Now you can choose to reduce your home energy bill
الآن يمكنك إختيار تقليل فاتورة كهرباء منزلك
by automatically cycling heavy loads
بتدوير الأحمال الثقيلة آلياً
like air conditioners and heaters.
مثل مكيفات الهواء والسخانات.
Hotels and businesses can shut down unused rooms
الفنادق والشركات يمكن أن تطفئ الغرف غير المستخدمة
from a central location, or even a cell phone.
من مركز تحكم أو حتى هاتف محمول.
There are 10 billion electrical outlets
هناك 10 بلايين مقبس كهربائي
in North America alone.
في أمريكا الشمالية لوحدها.
The potential energy savings is very, very significant.
قابلية الحفاظ على الطاقة هائلة جداً جداً.
So far we've applied for 414 patent claims.
حتى الآن لقد قدّمنا للحصول على 414 براءة إختراع .
Of those, 186 have been granted:
من تلك، 186 تم إعتمادها.
228 are in process.
228 تحت المعاينة.
And I'm pleased to announce that just three weeks ago
وأنا سعيد لأعلن أنه قبل ثلاثة أسابيع مضت
we received our first international recognition,
حصلنا على أول إعتراف عالمي،
the 2009 CES Innovation Award.
جائزة CES للإختراع لعام 2009
So, to conclude,
اذا، للتلخيص،
intelligent power can, globally, save thousands of lives,
الكهرباء الذكية يمكنها، عالمياً، إنقاذ آلالاف الأرواح،
prevent tens of thousands of injuries,
منع عشرات الآلاف من الجروح،
and eliminate tens of billions of dollars in property damage
وتقليل عشرات البلايين من الدولارات في دمار المنازل،
every single year,
كل عام،
while significantly reducing global energy consumption.
بينما تقلل بشدة إستهلاك الكهرباء عالمياً.
In the spirit of this year's TED Conference,
وفقاً لروح هذا العام لمؤتمر تيد،
we think this is a powerful, world-changing invention.
نعتقد أنه فعّال، إختراع سيغيّر العالم.
And I'd like to thank Chris for this opportunity
ونريد أن نشكر كريس على هذه الفرصة
to unveil our technology with you, and soon the world.
للكشف عن تكنلوجيتنا لكم، وقريباً الى العالم.
Thank you.
شكراً لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)